Privacy policy
--------------

Privacy policy
--------------

[Start](https://www.bplaced.net/) / Privacy policy

### 1\. Introduction

Taking care of and protecting your privacy is of paramount importance to bplaced.  
With the greatest care we process information transmitted to us exclusively on the basis of the statutory provisions (GDPR, TKG 2003).  
  
This statement provides information to help you understand how we collect, use and process your data when you visit bplaced.

### 2\. How and when we collect and process your personal data

bplaced collects, stores and processes information about each visitor and user of our services. This happens by accessing our website or using any of our services such as email.  
  
This information includes the name of the files accessed, the time of the request, status information for the connection, the domain or exact web address requested, the IP address (a number used to identify the client which made the request), information about the origin (the page previously visited, also known as referrer), and any information provided by the software used to access the file or service. This may include the operating system in use and other information.  
  
Thus, we collect, use and process the information provided to us without further consent, when necessary for order processing, billing or functionality of the respective service. This includes communication via email or participation in forum discussions and also includes any data for payment and/or order processing.  
  
Information collected by us may include personal data, such as mailing addresses, company data, email addresses, telephone numbers and, if necessary, fax numbers and details of payment methods, such as bank details.  
  
All data is processed, stored and revision-safe archived compliant to auditing requirements for no longer than 6 months after the period of data retention required by law. We do not use your data at any time for the creation of user profiles. The storage period may also depend on public interest and/or possible abuse prevention of our services as well as for the availability for inquiries with given legal basis.  

### 3\. Data security

All data available to us is treated confidentially and is protected against access by third parties to the best of our knowledge and belief in accordance with present and regularly evaluated technical and organisational measures and methods.  
  
The premises storing or processing the data are subject to permanent and documented access control, video surveillance, data mirroring with rapid recoverability in the event of loss in accordance with art. 32, 1c GDPR, ensuring an uninterruptible power supply, as well as procedures for our personnel for rapid handling and recovery for problems of any kind that may occur.  
  
Our employees are instructed to comply with sensitive handling of data in accordance with data protection criteria.  

### 4\. Sharing your information

We may need to share your information with other parties and service providers, when necessary or required to fulfill orders, such as domain registrars or certification authorities. Depending on the service used, this results in information being publicly available or publicly retrievable uopon request.  

This includes, in particular, contact details required for domains which are made accessible in public "whois" directories, or other technical information required for connectivity (such as IP addresses) and subscription periods (timestamps) associated with the domain.  
Also data is transmitted to payment service providers, registrars for domains, certification authorities for the issuance of certificates and printing companies commissioned with postal dispatch.  
  
Please note that exceptions for sharing your data may be justified on legal basis or debt collection.  
  
The obligation for employees with access to your data to maintain secrecy extends past their employment by TKG 2003.  
  
Your data will be treated with strict confidentiality and not be passed on to third parties for advertising purposes under no circumstances.  

### 5\. Contact

In order to ensure that our data is up-to-date and valid, it may be necessary for our employees to contact you. This is usually done by email or, if necessary, by phone. The contact information provided by you will be used exclusively for processing orders or for sign-up procedures.  
  
If you contact us via form on the website or by email, the data you provide will be stored for the purpose of processing your inquiry and in the event of follow-up questions. We do not pass on this information without your consent or legal basis.  

### 6\. Newsletter and Cookies

Our newsletter informs about news at bplaced. You are free to opt out by clicking on the link for that purpose at the bottom in each message or by opting out in your customer menu.  
  
Our websites use cookies. Cookies are text files that are stored on your system when you visit our websites and make it possible for us to recognize you as a visitor at a later point in time.  
  
We use such cookies to ensure the correct functionality of the websites and to make the overall experience easier for you. Most of these cookies are stored for the current session only. Some cookies remain stored on your system for a longer period of time (up to 60 days), so that we can identify you again for e.g. an automatic sign-in.  
Please note: the functionality of our services may be restricted, should you choose to disable cookies.  

Cookies that are not technically necessary may be rejected by click at any time.  

### 7\. Your rights

You are entitled to access, rectification, erasure, restriction, data portability, restriction and objection at any time. Should you wish to report a complaint or if you feel that bplaced has not addressed your concern in a satisfactory manner, you may contact your information commissioner's office.  
  
If you have any questions or other inqueries about our privacy policy, the data we hold on you, or you would like to exercise one of your data protection rights, please do not hesitate to contact us using our company contact page.  

Power die keine Grenzen kennt - seit 2007

WEBHOSTING

BUSINESS

WEBHOSTING & BUSINESS

SERVICES

SUPPORT

INFORMATION

SUPPORT & INFORMATION

FOLLOW US

MOBILE APPS

Get our app with support for 2-factor auth.entication

bplaced.net

© 2007 - 2024 bplaced

deutsch (Du) deutsch (Sie) english  

deutsch (Du) deutsch (Sie) english
